Map Collection
Hartford History Center, Hartford Public Library
Map Collection
1838-2004
Hartford History Center, Hartford Public Library Hartford, Connecticut
various
about 180 maps and atlases (about 72 cubic feet)
Maps tracing the development of the city of Hartford from the 1600s to the 2000s.
Historical Note
Maps in the Hartford History Center Collection cover the period from the seventeenth-century through the 2000s. Seventeenth-century maps are all later recreations. Most are based on research and surveys done by William S. Porter in 1838. Porter’s map of Hartford in 1640 was frequently reprinted and republished well into the twentieth century. Important nineteenth century maps include Marcus Smith’s 1850 Map of the City of Hartford and city atlases published by Baker & Tilden in 1869, by G. M. Hopkins in 1880, and by L. J. Richards in 1896. Twentieth-century maps include additional city atlases and maps produced by the City of Hartford Department of Engineering and the Metropolitan District Commission.
Scope and Content
The collection includes maps by many local surveyors and mapmakers, including Nathaniel Goodwin, Seth E. Marsh, William S. Porter, and Albert L. Washburn. The work of at least two women, Katherine C. Bartholomew and Ruth Goldie, is represented. The collection is arranged chronologically, based on date depicted, not on date published.
Access Restrictions
The records are stored in a restricted area and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Bartholomew, Katherine C., 1907-1992; Ellis, Arthur J., d. 1921; Goldie, James; Goldie, Ruth; Goodwin, Nathaniel, 1782-1855; Loomis, Frank W.; Marsh, Seth E., about 1823-1878; McClunie, Thomas; Porter, William S.; Richards, L. C.; Smith, Marcus; Spalding, D. G.; Washburn, Albert L., 1857-1948
Corporate Names
Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation); Aetna Casualty and Surety Company; Baker & Tilden; G. F. Warfield & Co.; Hartford (Conn.). Department of Engineering; Hartford (Conn.). Department of Housing and Community Development; Kellogg & Bulkeley; Metropolitan District Commission; Price & Lee Co.; Richards Map Company; Sanborn Map & Publishing Co.
Subjects
Cemeteries; Election districts; Highways; Historic sites; Maps; Parks; Reservoirs; Zoning
Geographic names
Hartford (Conn.); United States—History—Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775
Genre Terms
Maps; Topographc maps
Contents:
- Cabinet 1
  - The Map of Pioneer Hartford, Showing Early Landmarks and the Locations of Historical Events, pictorial map by James and Ruth Goldie,1927, 18.5 x 25 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - The Map of Pioneer Hartford, Showing Early Landmarks and the Locations of Historical Events, pictorial map by James and Ruth Goldie,1927 [another copy, colored], 18.5 x 25 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Hartford in 1640, arranged in 1838 from the old records and drawn by Wm. S. Porter,probably 1838, 14 x 22 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Hartford, Conn. 1639-1898, based upon Survey of Nat. Goodwin, City Surveyor, 1824,n.d., 16.5 x 13.25 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - 1635 Colonial Hartford and the Travelers, probably 1935, 12 x 18 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Hartford, Conn. 1639-1907, A.L. Washburn Del., Based upon Survey of Nat. Goodwin, City Surveyor, 1824, n.d., 16.75 x 13 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - [Map of Hartford in 1600s], n.d., blueprint, poor condition (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - Historic Spots of Old Hartford, Based upon Survey of Nat. Goodwin, City Surveyor, 1824, Hartford: Polygon Press, 1930, 14.25 x 11 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 3)
  - City of Hartford. Map of 4th Ward, From actual surveys under the direction of Seth E. Marsh, 1869, 21.5 x 16 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 3)
  - North Part, City of Hartford, Page 39 of a volume, 1893, 19.25 x 29.25 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 3)
  - Map of the City of Hartford, Surveyed by Marcus Smith, New York: M. Dripps, 1850, 23 x 17.75 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 3)
  - [Southwest Hartford], 23 x 17.5 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 3)
  - [Central and North Hartford], 23 x 17.75 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 3)
  - Index Map of the City of Hartford, Connecticut. Springfield: L.J. Richards & Co., 1896, 22 x 32 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 3)
  - Copy of a Map of the City of Hartford. Surveyed and Drawn by Marcus Smith, 1850, 1902, 21 x 26.5 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 3)
  - Plan of the City of Hartford Embodying topographical Surveys During Winter. 1892-1893, 29 x 17 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 3)
  - Map of Building Lots Property of J.C. Pratt, Esq., Hartford, Conn., by Thos. McClunie, 1897, 21 x 29 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 3)
  - Atlas of Hartford City and County with a Map of Connecticut from Actual Survey, Baker & Tilden, 1869, 18 x 14.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Atlas of Hartford City and County with a Map of Connecticut from Actual Survey [Copy 2], Baker & Tilden, 1869, 18 x 14.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - City Atlas of Hartford, Conn. Compiled and Published from Actual Surveys. Philadelphia: G. M. Hopkins, 1880, 17.75 x 14 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - City Atlas of Hartford, Conn. Compiled and Published from Actual Surveys [Copy2]. Philadelphia: G. M. Hopkins, 1880, 17.75 x 14 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 2)
  - Atlas of the City of Hartford, Connecticut Including, also, the Town of West Hartford L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 22.5 x 17.5 in. (Drawer 4, Folder 1)
  - Atlas of the City of Hartford, Connecticut Including, also, the Town of West Hartford [Copy 2], L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 22.5 x 17.5 in. (Drawer 4, Folder 2)
  - Atlas of the City of Hartford and Town of West Hartford, Conn., L.J. Richards &, Co., 1909, 22.5 x 17 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 1)
  - Part of Ward 8, City of Hartford, Plate 15, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 2)
  - Part of Ward 3, City of Hartford, Plate 25, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 3)
  - Part of Ward 6 & 9, City of Hartford, Plate 7, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 4)
  - Part of Ward 10, City of Hartford, Plate 18, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 5)
  - Part of Ward 3, City of Hartford, Plate 23, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 6)
  - Part of Ward 7 & 8, City of Hartford, Plate 13, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 7)
  - Part of Ward 4, 5 & 9, City of Hartford, Plate 3, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 8)
  - Part of Ward 8 & 10, City of Hartford, Plate 16, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 9)
  - Part of Ward 7, City of Hartford, Plate 9, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 10)
  - Part of Ward 2 & 3, City of Hartford, Plate 26, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 11)
  - Part of Ward 1, 2 & 6, City of Hartford, Plate 1, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 12)
  - Part of Ward 10, City of Hartford, Plate 6, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 13)
  - Part of Ward 8 & 10, City of Hartford, Plate 17, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 14)
  - Part of Ward 9, City of Hartford, Plate 5, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 15)
  - Part of Ward 7, City of Hartford, Plate 10, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 16)
  - Part of Ward 8, City of Hartford, Plate 12, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 17)
  - Part of Ward 2, 3 & 4, City of Hartford, Plate 22, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 18)
  - Part of Ward 1, 6 & 9, City of Hartford, Plate 8, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 19)
  - Part of Ward 5 & 6, City of Hartford, Plate 4, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 20)
  - Part of Ward 7, City of Hartford, Plate 11, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 21)
  - Part of Ward 5, City of Hartford, Plate 24, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 22)
  - Part of Ward 4 & 10, City of Hartford, Plate 20, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 23)
  - Part of Ward 4 & 10, City of Hartford, Plate 19, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 24)
  - Part of Ward 3 & 4, City of Hartford, Plate 21, L.J. Richards &, Co., 1896, 32.5 x 22 in. (Drawer 5, Folder 25)
  - Atlas of the City of Hartford and West Hartford, Connecticut from Actual Surveys and City Records. New York: Sanborn Map Company, 1917, 24.5 x 20 in. (Drawer 6, Folder 1)
  - Map of Zion Hill Cemetery. Frank W. Loomis, [n.d.], 26.5 x 19.5 in. (Drawer 7, Folder 1)
  - Atlas of the City of Hartford and West Hartford, Connecticut from Actual Surveys and City Records. New York: Sanborn Map Company, 1921, 24.5 x 20 in. (Drawer 7, Folder 2)
  - Map of Hartford Area, Connecticut, Showing rock outcrops, wooded areas, and ground-water conditions. A.J. Ellis, 1917, 24.75 x 21 in. (Drawer 8, Folder 1)
  - Map of the City of Hartford. Hartford Department of Engineering, [n.d.], 28 x 42 in. (Drawer 8, Folder 1)
  - Map of the City of Hartford. Hartford Department of Engineering, 1929, 26 x 38 in. (Drawer 8, Folder 1)
  - Richards Standard Map of the City of Hartford, Connecticut. Springfield, Mass.: Richards Map Company, 1912, 22.5 x 32.25 in. (Drawer 8, Folder 1)
  - Elihu Geer Sons' New Map of the City of Hartford, Connecticut [has historical sites added in manuscript]. Hartford: Hartford Printing Co., 1926, 16 x 25 in. (Drawer 8, Folder 1)
  - Map of the city of Hartford. Regional Planning commission of the Metropolitan District, 1937, 25 x 34 in. (Drawer 8, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee Co., 1934, 26 x 26 in. (Drawer 8, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee Co., 1939, 26 x 26 in. (Drawer 8, Folder 2)
  - Plan of the City of Hartford. Hartford: Department of Engineering, 1932, 29.5 x 42.5 in. (Drawer 8, Folder 2)
  - Map of the City of Hartford Showing Wards and Precincts. Hartford: Department of Engineering, 1939, 24.5 x 34 in. (Drawer 8, Folder 2)
  - A Cultural and Historical Map of Hartford. [Hartford]: Kellogg & Bulkeley, 1933, 27.75 x 22 in. (Drawer 8, Folder 2)
  - Map of Connecticut…Issued in Commemoration of the State's Tercentenary. On verso: Historical Sketches of Connecticut's Seventeen Original Towns and A Few of Connecticut's Many Historical Landmarks [Hartford]: Aetna Casualty & Surety Company, 1935, 18.25 x 32 in. (Drawer 8, Folder 2)
  - Map of Hartford Connecticut Prepared by the Federal Writers ProjectWorks Progress Administration, 1938, 71 x 41 in. (Drawer 8, Folder 2)
  - [Contour Map of Hartford Area], n.d., 31 x 41 in. (Drawer 10, Folder 1)
  - City of Hartford. Department of Engineering, [n.d.], 27 x 37 in. (Drawer 10, Folder 1)
  - Hartford, Conn. C.S. Hammond & Co.; from Hammond's Ambassador Atlas Index Section. New York: C.S. Hammond & Co., [1961], 16.5 x 10.25 in. (Drawer 10, Folder 1)
  - Latest Map of Hartford, Connecticut [cover only]. Hartford: G.F. Warfield & Co., n.d., 19 x 33.75 in. (Drawer 10, Folder 1)
- Cabinet 2
  - Map of Business District, Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Central Maps Co., 1941, 19 x 33.75 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of Business District, Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Central Maps Co., 1945, 19 x 33.75 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of Business District, Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Central Maps Co., 1948, 25 x 36 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Zoning Map of City of Hartford. Hartford: Department of Engineering, 1945, 25.75 x 33.5 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of the City of Hartford Showing Wards and Precincts. Hartford: Department of Engineering, 1948, 24.5 x 33.5 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of the City of Hartford. Hartford: Department of Engineering, 1946, 24.5 x 33.5 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee, [1940], 28 x 26.5 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee, [1941], 28 x 26.5 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee, [1948], 28 x 26.5 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee, [1949], 28 x 26.5 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee, [n.d.], 28 x 26.5 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of the City of Hartford. Hartford: Department of Engineering, 1953, 22.25 x 31 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of the City of Hartford. Hartford: Department of Engineering, 1954 (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - Map of the City of Hartford. Hartford: Department of Engineering, [1955] (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - Map of Business District, Hartford, Conn.. Hartford: Central Maps Co., 1954, 25.5 x 36 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: The Price & Lee Co., [1950], 28 x 27 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: The Price & Lee Co., 1951-1952 (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: The Price & Lee Co., 1952 (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: The Price & Lee Co., 1953 (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: The Price & Lee Co., 1954 (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: The Price & Lee Co., 1955 (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: The Price & Lee Co., 1956 (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: The Price & Lee Co., 1957 (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: The Price & Lee Co., 1958 (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: The Price & Lee Co., 1959 (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - Map of the Metropolitan District and Environs. [Hartford]: Metropolitan District, 1956, 36.5 x 54 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - Geodetic and Topographical Survey. Sheet 17. [Hartford]: Metropolitan District, 1956, 22 x 28 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - Geodetic and Topographical Survey. Sheet 38. [Hartford]: Metropolitan District, 1956, 22 x 28 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - Geodetic and Topographical Survey. Sheet 67. [Hartford]: Metropolitan District, 1956, 22 x 28 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - Geodetic and Topographical Survey. Sheet 34. [Hartford]: Metropolitan District, 1956, 22 x 28 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - Geodetic and Topographical Survey. Sheet 66. [Hartford]: Metropolitan District, 1956, 22 x 28 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - Geodetic and Topographical Survey. Sheet 35. [Hartford]: Metropolitan District, 1956, 22 x 28 in. (Drawer 1, Folder 2)
  - Hartford/West Hartford. January 1966. Sheet 13. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1966, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford/West Hartford. January 1966. Sheet 14. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1966, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford/West Hartford. January 1966. Sheet 15. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1966, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford/West Hartford. January 1966. Sheet 16. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1966, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford/West Hartford. January 1966. Sheet 30. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1966, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford, April 1964. Sheet 36. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1964, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford/Bloomfield. April 1961. Sheet 56. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1961, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford/Windsor/Bloomfield. January 1960. Sheet 57. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1960, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford, April, 1964. Sheet 58. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1964, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford, December, 1962. Sheet 59. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1962, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford, December, 1962. Sheet 60. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1962, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford, December, 1966. Sheet 61. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1966, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford, April, 1964. Sheet 63. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1964, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford, December, 1964. Sheet 64. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1964, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford/Westhersfield. April, 1961. Sheet 65. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1961, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford, December, 1967. Sheet 93. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1967, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford, December, 1967. Sheet 94. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1967, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford/East Hartford, Jan. 1966. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1966, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - East Hartford/Hartford, Jan., 1966. Sheet 96. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1966, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford/East Hartford, Dec. 1962. Sheet 97. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1962, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford. March, 1965. Sheet 98. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1965, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford. March, 1965. Sheet 99. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1965, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford/Wethersfield. March, 1965. Sheet 100. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1965, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford/Wethersfield/South Windsor. Jan., 1960. Sheet 135. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1960, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - East Hartford/Hartford. Jan., 1966. Sheet 138. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1966, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford/East Hartford. March, 1965. Sheet 140. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1965, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford/East Hartford. March, 1965. Sheet 141. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1965, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartford/East Hartford. April, 1960. Sheet 142. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1960, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - Wethersfield/Hartford/East Hartford/Glastonbury. April, 1964. Sheet 143. Abrams Aerial Survey Corporation, 1964, 11 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 1)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee Co., 1960, 27.75 x 27.5 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee Co., 1961, 27.75 x 27.5 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee Co., 1962, 27.75 x 27.5 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee Co., 1963, 27.75 x 27.5 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee Co., 1964, 27.75 x 27.5 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee Co., 1965, 27.75 x 27.5 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee Co., 1967, 27.75 x 27.5 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. On verso: New Map of East Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Price & Lee Co., [1968], 27.75 x 27.5 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - Map of the City of Hartford. [Hartford]: Metropolitan District, 1969, 33 x 30 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - Map of the Metropolitan District and Environs. [Hartford]: Metropolitan District, 1969, 40.5 x 58.25 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - Map of the Metropolitan District and Environs. [Hartford]: Metropolitan District, 1961, 36.5 x 56 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - The Capitol Region. Capitol Region Planning Agency, 1964, 31 x 40 in. (Drawer 2, Folder 2)
  - Urban Atlas: Tract Data for Standard Metropolitan Statistical Areas. Washington, D.C.: United States Department of Commerce, 1974, 17 x 22 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - Map of the City of Hartford. [Hartford]: Metropolitan District, 1970, 16.5 x 15 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - City of Hartford. Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1974, 17 x 16 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - City of Hartford. Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1975, 17 x 16 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - City of Hartford. Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1976, 17 x 17.5 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - City of Hartford. Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1978, 17 x 17.5 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - City of Hartford. Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1979, 17 x 18 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. New Haven: Price & Lee Co., [1970], 22 x 17 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. New Haven: Price & Lee Co., [1971], 22 x 17 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - New Map of Hartford and West Hartford, Conn. New Haven: Price & Lee Co., [n.d.], 21 x 17.75 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - Voting Districts/City of Hartford. Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1973, 23 x 32 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - The Metropolitan District and Environs. Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1975, 58.5 x 40.25 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - The Metropolitan District and Environs. Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1978, 58.5 x 40.25 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - Geodetic and Topographical Maps. Sheet 17. [Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1973], 22 x 28 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - Geodetic and Topographical Maps. Sheets 34-38. [Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1973], 22 x 28 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - Geodetic and Topographical Maps. Sheets 60-61. [Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1973], 22 x 28 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - Geodetic and Topographical Maps. Sheets 66-67. [Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1973], 22 x 28 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - Geodetic and Topographical Maps. Sheets 95-97. [Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1973], 22 x 28 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - City of Hartford/Hartford Zoning Ordinance District Map. Commission on the City Plan, 1985, 38 x 27.75 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 2)
  - City of Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1980, 17.5 x 18 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 2)
  - City of Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1981, 33 x 29.25 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 2)
  - City of Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1982, 24 x 18 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 2)
  - City of Hartford, Conn. Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1985, 58.25 x 40.75 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 2)
  - Future Land Use/Plan of Development. Hartford: Commission on the City Plan, 1985, 29.75 x 22.75 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 2)
  - A View of Downtown Hartford. Hartford: The Hartford Courant, 1983, 31.75 x 23.75 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 2)
  - A View of Hartford. Hartford: The Hartford Courant, [n.d.], 35.75 x 24 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 2)
  - Greater Hartford. Toronto: Archar, Inc., 1980, 28.25 x 38.5 in. (Drawer 3, Folder 2)
  - Welcome to Hartford. Hartford: Convention and Visitors Bureau, 1998, 11 x 26 in. (Drawer 4, Folder 1)
  - City of Hartford, Connecticut. Hartford: Metropolitan District, 1993, 32.5 x 29 in. (Drawer 4, Folder 1)